William Steimel

Ai Koto 102 5-23-15

Koenji-Minami, Suginami-ku

Tokyo, Japan

070-4282-5179

steimel64.github.io

July 17, 2019

Dear Human Resources Manager:

Both my academic coursework and practical work experience have prepared me to not only be responsive to workplace needs, but have also provided a comprehensive analytical background, which is ideally suited to the job responsibilities and functions associated with the Data Scientist position.

My coursework in Business Administration at Felician University as well as the time I spent studying abroad at Kansai Gaidai University has given me strong interpersonal skills and valuable experience in effectively working with teams in a variety of contexts. Being awarded the MEXT scholarship by the Japanese government has also afforded me the opportunity to study Green Science and Engineering at Sophia University and United Nations University where I am currently studying a combination of Machine Learning and Sustainability Science.

In addition, my 3 years of professional experience as an I&O Analyst and IT Service Manager at ADP has contributed to my background in data analytics where I utilized technical skills in Python/R to drive continual service improvement, process optimization, and cost savings throughout the organization. This role required me to combine an understanding of complex data structures, technical scripting in R/Python/SQL, as well as the domain knowledge needed to deliver effective service to customers.

I believe my skills and various experiences are ideally suited to what Uniqlo is seeking in a Data Scientist. I am available for an interview at your convenience, and can be reached via phone at 070-4282-5179 or via email at steimel65@gmail.com.

Thank you and I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Sincerely,

William Steimel

William Steimel

❖E: steimel65@gmail.com ❖ M: 070-4282-5179 ❖ LI: linkedin.com/in/steimelw ❖ github: steimel64.github.io/

EDUCATION

Sophia University

Tokyo, Japan

Master of Science in Green Science and Engineering September 2017 - Present

- Research Area: Machine Learning
- Joint Diploma in Sustainability Studies: United Nations University
- Monbukagakusho Scholarship (MEXT Scholarship) Recipient

Masters Thesis: A Time Independent Gradient Boosting Machine for Rent Prediction in Tokyo 23 Special Wards with Geospatial and Environmental Features

Felician University

Lodi. NJ

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

September 2010 - May 2015

- Minor: Global Peace and Justice Studies
- Summa Cum Laude

Kansai Gaidai University Asian Studies Program

Osaka, Japan

September 2012 - June 2013

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lombard Inc. (CodExa)

Tokyo, Japan

Machine Learning Intern

Feb 2018 - Present

- Co-authored article published in Nikkei Software on the basics of Machine Learning (Nov 2018)
- Analyzed data from internal affiliate marketing application to get insight into partner behavior

Roseland, NJ

IT Service Manager

May 2017 - September 2017

- Analyzed budgets totaling millions of dollars for technical projects to ensure proper allocation of resources
- Maintained documentation, reports, and KPI scorecards vital to the Change Management process
- Managed weekly Change Management process improvement meetings in collaboration with CAB
- Identified applications impacted by EU GDPR/BCR Statutory Requirements and associated PII data

I&O Analyst

June 2015 - May 2017

- Responsible for implementing reporting automation and statistical analysis to facilitate process optimization, capacity/demand forecasting, service level management, and audit compliance
- Created and presented executive dashboards and scorecards to show the trends in data using R/Excel
- Used SQL Server/R programming skills to create automated data cleaning/extraction scripts
- Created interactive Tableau Dashboards revealing insight into ADP's Operational performance
- Organized and developed technical process documents and evidence for ISO 9000 and 20000 Audits
- Developed business cases through available data to justify key projects to upper management
- Supported consultants as process analyst for successful migration to risk based change process

Intern (IT Service Mgmt/Project Mgmt)

February 2015 - May 2015

- Supported service management team in documentation management via MS Sharepoint/Jive/Jira
- Monitored monthly request, incident, problem, and change metrics against targets
- Created interactive training on Change Management Process through LMS Software for 1500 users

Felician University Global Academic Initiatives

Lodi. NJ

NGO Representative to the United Nations DPI

January 2015 - June 2015

Participated at weekly briefings organized by UN DPI on topics related to social justice and diplomacy

Felician University

Lodi, NJ July 2013 - May 2015

Research Assistant

Coordinated with staff members to manage primary reporting activities associated with student feedback

June 2011 - August 2012 **Systems Assistant**

Developed statistical reports for campus wide departments through SQL Server and Crystal Reports

LEADERSHIP

"Policy Imperatives for Women's Health Research and Development" Spring 2015

- Delivered speech at the inaugural "World Women's Health and Development Forum" at the UN
- Researched world labor force participation rates and proposed youth vision to reducing gender inequality

SKILLS

- Tools: Tableau, Git, GIS, Visio, SAP Business Objects, Advanced Excel (Pivot Table/Vlookup)
- Programming Languages: Python (pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, scikit-learn), R, SQL
- Machine Learning: Regression, Random Forests, Neural Networks, Clustering, Gradient Boosting

CERTIFICATIONS

• ITIL v3-Foundations, Understanding BS ISO/IEC 20000-1:2011, JLPT N2